心の声
（ノノハ）南の島の　海辺のリゾート。
A seaside resort on a tropical island...
心の声
パズルのことは　全部忘れて
のんびりできる…。
We can finally forget about puzzles and just relax...
みんな　行っくよ～！
Okay, guys! Here we go!
そ～れ！
…と思ってきたのに…。
心の声
...or so I thought.
（カイト）よっしゃ～！
（ギャモン）かぁぐっ…。
Done!
へへっ。　今回も　俺の勝ちだぜ。
I won again.
まぐれが続くと思うなよ！
Your luck won't last forever!
（エレナ）３０秒経過！
That's 30 seconds!
（キュービック）解けた！
（アナ）アナも！
Solved!
Me too!
（エレナ）ちょっと　何やってんのよ
ガリレオ。　もう　時間ないわよ！
What are you doing, Galileo? Time is up!
I won't lose to this puzzle!
はぁ。　私は　何で
ここに居るんだろう…。
Why am I here again?
lost te saguri de sagashiteta
Lost, trying to find it blindly with my hands.
tozasareta mirai no kotae nante doko ni mo nai
But the key to the locked future is nowhere to be found.
hashiru shoudou ima kaidoku funou
Undecipherable urges surging.
found kudaketa hazu no unmei wo
I found the fate I believed broken.
mijukuna yume no naka de kikoetekitan da
I heard it in my immature dream.
saigo made I'll be there for you
I'll be there for you till the very end.
tachitomaranai kono hari dake wa
I can't stop. I hear nothing else.
boku no asu wo kizamu oto tsukisasu
How this needle carves my future.
shinjitsu kara nigetara ima
I'm running away from the truth now.
genjitsu ni mo maketara ima
I'm losing to reality now.
nani ga nokoru no (nokoru no)
What will be left?
kazoekirenai kono kizu dake ga
The countless scars on my body
boku no kinou wo zanzou toshite kataru
are the only thing telling the story of my past.
unmei ga hodokete mo ima
Even if fate falls apart now,
sonzai wo kowashite mo ima
even if existence shatters now,
boku no michi wo yuku yo
I'm walking down my own path.
It's now or never.
This is what they say: "Live your life today."
There will always be, there will always be a way.
Even Nonoha Wants To Solve!
Puzzle Power Camp: 4 Days Remaining
心の声
みんなで　思いっきり
遊ぼうと思って　来たのに→
I came here hoping we could all have fun together,
合宿になったら　私
心の声
やることないじゃん…。
but now that it's turned into a power camp, I have nothing to do.
おまけに…。
心の声
And what's even worse...
（キュービック）
あ～！　なんだか　パズル能力が
どんどん上がってる気がするな！
It feels like my puzzle skills are improving every second!
アナも～！
（ソウジ）頼もしいね。
Me too!
Looks like you're having fun.
（ギャモン）
女王様のしごきが厳しいからな。
It's thanks to the mistress's harsh training.
（エレナ）ふん　感謝するのね。
At least you're grateful.
今の僕たち４人なら
オルペウス・オーダーなんて→
The Orpheus Order won't stand a chance against the four of us now!
全然　相手じゃないね。
全然　全然。
No chance, no chance!
言ってくれるじゃん。
頼りにしてるぜ！　お二人さん。
That's the right attitude!
We'll be counting on you two!
≫（アナ）うん　頼られた～！
I'm being counted on!
≫（キュービック）何だよ　バカにして～！
≫（ギャモン）バカになんて　してねえよ。
Don't make fun of me!
No one's making fun of you...
カイトや　ギャモン君は
心の声
ともかく　出会ったころは→
Kaito and Gammon are one thing,
but Cubie and Ana weren't interested in puzzles at first, yet they're having so much fun...
心の声
パズルに興味がなかった　キューちゃんや
アナまで　あんなに楽しそう。
（タマキ）会長のカレーに　隠し味で　リンゴを
すって　入れてみたんですけど。
I tried adding some extra taste to your curry recipe with apple vinegar.
ん　うん。
（タマキ）お口に合いますか？
Do you like it?
But I... I...
なのに…　私は…。
心の声
そう来たか！
ん！？
なら　これで　どうだ！
I was expecting this!
How about this then?
う～ん！　だったら　俺は…。
Take this!
カイト！　ギャモン君！
食事中に　パズルしない！
Kaito! Gammon! No puzzles while you're eating!
キューちゃん！
食事中にパソコンしない！
Cubie! No computers while you're eating!
ん～。
アナも絵を描かない！
Ana, no painting either!
ぜ～んぶ　没収！
（一同）え～っ！？
These are all confiscated!
食事終わるまで　禁止！
They're banned until dinner's over!
でも　パズルのデザインを
インプットしなくちゃ。
But I have to input the puzzle design...
アナのイメージ　爆発中なのに～。
But inspiration just exploded in me!
返せ！
そうだ。　男と男の勝負を！
Give it back!
Yeah! Don't get in the way of a man's fight!
No talking back!
まだ　言うか！
（ギャモン・カイト）ぐっぐっ～。
ノノハの鬼！　悪魔！
鬼～！　悪魔～！
Nonoha, you monster! Demon!
Monster! Demon!
うるさ～い！
（ミハル）もう！　兄ちゃん。
Shut up!
Gosh darn it, Gammon!
You too, Itou. Don't start fights during meals!
（タマキ）井藤さんも
食事中に暴れない！
（エレナ）全く騒がしい。
（アイリ）皆さん　元気ですね！
Everyone's so fired up!
（タマキ）明日の買い出し当番は…。
（ミハル）あっ　私です。
Who's going shopping tomorrow?
Oh, I am!
じゃあ　あさっては　私
しあさっては　井藤さん→
Then I'll go the day after tomorrow,
the day after that is Itou, and the last day is Mizutani.
最終日は　水谷さん　お願いね。
（アイリ・ノノハ）分かりました。
Okay?
Roger that!
ん～！
ノノハ先輩のスイーツ　おいしいです。→
Nonoha, your cookies are so delicious!
お料理も最高だし　先輩が
来てくれて　ホント助かりました。
And you're so great at cooking too. I'm really glad you're here!
あぁ　ありがとう。
Thanks.
私も　パズルが解ければ
みんなと一緒に　楽しめるのかな。
If I could solve puzzles, then I could have fun with everyone else...
えっ！？　プレゼント！？
回想
Huh, a present?
うん。　目つぶって　手を出して。
Yeah!
Close your eyes and hold out your hands!
こう？
回想
イヒヒヒッ。
Like this?
回想
ふ～ん。
目　開けていいよ。
You can open your eyes now.
回想
うっ！
じゃじゃ～ん！　イヒヒヒッ。
もう！　私が　パズル苦手なの
回想
知ってるくせに！
You know I stink at puzzles!
回想
へへ～ん！
悔しかったら　解いてみな～！
If you don't like it, try solving it!
こら～！　カイト！
回想
へははははっ！
Get back here! Kaito!
うふっ…　よ～し！
All right!
ということで　今日から　私も
一緒にパズルの特訓する。
So, starting today, I'm gonna improve my puzzle skills too!
Huh?
はあ！？
何　言ってんだよ！？
What are you talking about?
…んなの　お前に
できるわけねえだろ。
Just give up already.
You can't know unless you try!
やってみなけりゃ
分かんないでしょ。
いや　分かるって。
まっ　いいわ。
Oh, yes I can.
Well, fine by me.
おい　エレナ！
マジかよ！？
Elena?!
Seriously?!
やった！　ありがとう。　エレナさん。
Hurray! Thanks, Elena!
ついて来られるなら
ついてらっしゃい。
Let's see if you can keep up with the pace!
制限時間　１０分！
知恵の輪　１００本！
Time limit is ten minutes! 100 puzzle links!
用意　スタート！
And... go!
お～～！　くりゃ！　うぉ～！
だぁ～！　お～い！　だぁ～！
制限時間　１０分！　組木パズル　２００個！
用意　スタート！
Time limit is ten minutes! 200 wood cubes!
And... go!
は～～！　と　せい！　は～！
うりゃ～！　てっぽい！
とりゃ～！
え～と…　え～と…　え～っと…。
300-stick mountain!
三つ山崩し　３００本！　用意　スタート！
And... go!
う～　カイト！
う～　マンボ！
Kaito!
Mambo!
Uh... 300... Um...
え～と…　３００…　えっ！？
え～っと…。
はぁ…　はぁ…　エレナさん。
何？
Elena...
What's up?
ノド渇いちゃった。
水とか　ないかな？
I'm thirsty.
Can I get some water?
パ…　パズル解かなきゃ　ダメなの？
うん。
I have to solve a puzzle for it?
Yeah.
おなか　すいたんだけど…。
I'm kinda hungry...
やっぱり…。
I thought so.
トイレ　トイレ…。
Crap, I gotta go!
あれ？　ん！？　う～ん！
ふ～ん！　うんうん！
はぁ…　はぁ…　うっ！？
マジっすか？
You gotta be kidding me.
あ～！
いいかげん　ギブして弁当もらえよ！
Just give up and eat.
絶対　いや。
Never!
Why do you want to start puzzles now?
（エレナ）どうして　いきなり　特訓に
参加したいなんて言い出したの？
ど　どうしてって　オルペウス・オーダーって
強いみたいだし→
Well, it's just that the Orpheus guys are strong,
私も　パズル解ければ　みんなの役に
立てるかな～　なんて。
so I thought could help out if I could solve puzzles too... kinda.
はぁ…！？
おう！　アントワネット。　腹ごなしだ。
Okay, Antoinette, I'm full!
次のパズル　さっさと行こうぜ。
It's time for the next puzzle!
ホントに。　食べるか　パズルするかしか
ないんだから…。
Are food and puzzles all you care about?
おう！？
（ギャモン）何だ！？
迷路？
Huh?
A maze?
この迷路！
This maze...
ミノタウロスの！？
The Minotaur's!
The one that was behind the academy?
学園の裏山にあったっていう
あれか？
そういや　そうだ。
Now that you mention it...
すべての賢者のパズル
愚者のパズルができるの。
You can do all the Sage and Fools' Puzzles with this.
もっとも　すでに解かれた
パズルのみだけどね。
Well, only the ones that are already solved to be exact.
私にやらせて！
ノノハ！
Let me do it!
Nonoha!
へへ～ん　早い者勝ちってね！
…ったく…。
I got to it first!
Oh, please.
へっ　いいじゃねえか。
ノノハなら　すぐに　とちって…。
Well, whatever...
Nonoha will just give-
What?!
な～い！？
なんつ～　スピードだ！
So fast!
This one's the Demon Girl's puzzle!
こいつは！？　鬼の手姫のパズル！
やるじゃない！
Not bad!
Nonoha's solving puzzles!
ノノハが　パズルを解いてはる！？
別に　驚くこっちゃねえよ。
It's no surprise.
忘れたのか？　ノノハの記憶力。
記憶力？
Have you forgotten about Nonoha's memory?
Memory?
ノノハは　一度見たもんは
絶対に忘れねえ。
If she sees something, she'll never forget it.
パズルを解いてるわけじゃねえ。
覚えた解き方を再現してるだけだ。
She's not solving the puzzles, she's just remembering how they were solved.
エレナさんのミニチュアパズル。
この時　カイトは…。
Elena's mini-town puzzle!
Kaito did it like this...
このパズルは…。
This one...
あれ！？　えっ？
Huh? What's this?
これ　何だろう…。
ん～　えい！
（電子音）
あちゃ～！　ミスった～！
Darn, I messed up...
何で　急に　しくじったんだ？
Why did she stop suddenly?
あのパズルを　俺が解いたとき
ノノハは　そこに居なかった…。
She wasn't there when I solved that puzzle.
いい線　いったでしょう！
私だって　やればできるんだから。
Whatevs, I got pretty far.
See! I can do it if I try!
ノノハは　無理して
パズルすることねえって！
Nonoha, you don't have to force yourself to do puzzles!
えっ！？
大丈夫。
It's okay.
Whatever the Orpheus Order comes up with next, we'll solve all their puzzles!
オルペウス・オーダーが　どんなパズルで
攻めてきたって→
俺たちが　全部　解いてやるからよ。
俺たち…。
おう！
We?
Yeah!
俺様に任せておけば
何の心配も要らねえって。
Just leave it to me! No need to worry!
ううっ。
そうだよね…　みんな　居るもんね。
Yeah, that's right... You're all here...
みんな…　パズル上手だもんね…。
You're all so good with puzzles...
みんなか　どうかは
分かんねえけどな。
But it's not "all of us"...
あっ　全くだ！
Yeah, exactly!
私は　みんなの中に入れないんだ。
I can't be a part of it.
あっ？　何か言ったか？
Did you say something?
私　帰るね。
（ギャモン）はぁ！？
I'm going back.
Huh?
慣れないこと
するもんじゃないわね。
I shouldn't do what I'm not good at.
頭　疲れちゃった。
My brain's tired too.
私　夕飯作ってるから
早く帰ってきてね。
I'm making dinner, so come back soon!
じゃ！
おう！
Later!
Yeah!
ノノハのやつ　なんか
おかしくなかったか？
Wasn't Nonoha acting weird?
そうか？
Was she?
大丈夫。　オルペウス・オーダーが
回想
どんなパズルで攻めてきたって→
Whatever the Orpheus Order comes up with next, we'll solve all their puzzles!
回想
俺たちが　全部　解いてやるからよ。
私は…　みんなの中に…。
I can't be a part of it.
へへ～ん！
回想
悔しかったら　解いてみな～！
If you don't like it, try solving it!
ううん…　諦めない…
まずは　ここから。
No!
I won't give up.
I'm gonna start from here.
合宿が終わるまでに　このパズルを…。
I'll solve this puzzle before camp ends.
（ギャモン）はい　おまたへ！
副会長は　オムライス。
Here you go!
Rice omelet for the vice prez.
（タマキ）ありがとう。
…んで　軸川先輩は　リンゴチャンプルー。
Thanks.
Apple champloo for Jikugawa.
ありがとう。
ほ～ら！　ミハル。
Thanks.
Look, Miharu!
俺様特製　海の幸たっぷり
焼きそばだぜ～！
It's my special seafood fried noodles!
いただきま～す。
Let's eat then.
みんな！
食事中に　他のことしない！
Guys, don't play during meals!
は～い。
（アナ）ほ～い。
'Kay...
（キュービック）もうちょっと…。
Just a little longer...
はあ！　逆之上君
妹さんの世話もいいけど→
Sakanoue, it's one thing to look after your sister,
自分の食事も　ちゃんとしなさい！
but you should eat as well!
ほ～ら　ミハル　あ～ん。
Come on, Miharu. Say "ah"!
だから　１人で　できるって。
まったく…。
I can eat by myself!
For Pete's sake.
That's how it goes...
困ったもんだね。
ノノハは　どうしたの？
What about our little Nonoha?
姫川さん！
先輩には「さん」を付けなさい。
Ms. Himekawa, that's not how you talk about your senior!
ノ…　ノノハさんは？
Ah, so where is Nonoha?
やりたいことがあるから　食事は
お部屋で取るって言ってましたよ。
She said she's busy with something and is eating in her room.
（エレナ）やりたいこと？
Busy?
Puzzle Power Camp: 3 Days Remaining
え～　次が白だから　え～っと？
Next from the white... uh...
残り時間　２０秒。
Twenty seconds left!
もっと　もっと　左だって。
分かってるよ。　うるせえな！
I said move more to the left!
Shut up!
これが　たぶん　角に入るんだな。
残り　１分！
I think this will be a corner!
One minute left!
Puzzle Power Camp: 2 Days Remaining
は～い　ミハル。
だから　１人で　できるってば！
Come on, Miharu!
I told you I can eat by myself!
あっ！？
何だか　雰囲気が…。
Something's off...
会長　大門君たちの様子
おかしくありませんか？
President, don't you think the boys are acting weird?
（タマキ）
キュービック君やアナさんも　部屋から
出なくなってしまいましたし…。
Cubic and Ana aren't coming out of their rooms either.
そうだねぇ。
どうしたんだろうねぇ？
Yeah. I wonder what's wrong.
何？　こんな所に呼び出して…。
Why did you call me out here?
（エレナ）聞きたいのは　こっちの方。
I'm the one asking questions here.
１人で　一体　何してるの？
What were you doing alone all this time?
実は…。
Actually...
Huh? A puzzle?
えっ！？　パズルを！？
うん　合宿が終わるまでに
絶対　解くって決めたんだ。
Yeah. I decided to solve it before the end of the power camp.
役に立ちたいから？
うっ！
Because you want to be useful?
ううん。
私の居場所がないみたいで。
No...
Because there's no place for me here.
Huh?
You're all connected by puzzles... I'm the only one left out.
だって　みんなは　パズルで　しっかり
つながってるのに　私だけ…。
はぁ…　分かってないんだ。
You don't get it...
で　もし　そのパズルが解けなかったら
どうするつもり？
And what if you can't solve it?
Huh?
えっ！？
そのパズルが解けなかったら→
What if you can't solve it and there's still have no place for you?
居場所の無いあなたは　どうする
つもりだって　聞いてるのよ？
If I can't solve it...
もし　解けなかったら…。
解けなかったら　私　もう
みんなと一緒に居られない！
I can't stay with you guys any longer.
Puzzle Power Camp: 1 Day Remaining
心の声
（アイリ）カイト先輩は　パズルに夢中で→
Kaito is absorbed in a puzzle...
心の声
キュービック君は　何か研究があるとかで
アナ先輩は　絵を描いていて→
Cubic is researching something...
Ana is painting...
ギャモン先輩は　あんまり
心の声
しつこく世話を焼くもんだから→
Gammon annoyed her so much that Miharu went somewhere alone...
ミハルちゃん　１人で
心の声
遊びに行っちゃって…。
くすん…。
President!
会長。
困ったもんだね。
That's how it goes.
うはっ。　ん。
心の声
絶対…　絶対に…。
I'm...
going to...
解いてみせる。
心の声
solve this for sure!
やっぱり…　解けなかった。
In the end, I couldn't solve it.
ノノハさん…。
どうしたの？　アイリちゃん！？
Nonoha...
What's wrong? Airi!
（ミハル）朝食の材料がないんです。
えっ！？
We've got nothing left for breakfast!
What?!
きのうは　私が
買い出し当番だったんですけど→
I went shopping yesterday, but I was so absorbed buying other supplies that I forgot to get food.
生活用品　買うのに
気を取られて→
食材買ってくるの
忘れちゃったんです…。
（ミハル）今から　町に　買い物に
行ったんじゃ　間に合わないし…。
Even if I went to town now, I wouldn't make it back fast enough...
カイト先輩も　ギャモン先輩も　朝ごはん
抜きになったら　怒るだろうな。
Kaito and Gammon will get mad if they don't get breakfast.
助けてください。　ノノハ先輩。
Please help me, Nonoha!
Please! We don't know what to do!
（ミハル）お願いします。　私たち　もう
どうしていいか　分からなくって。
Okay.
ミハルちゃん　あっちの一番下の
段ボールに　卵が残ってないか→
Miharu, check if there are any eggs left in that box at the bottom.
見てきて。　アイリちゃんは　冷蔵庫。
ハムとバターが　まだあったはず。
Airi, you check the fridge. There should be some ham and butter left.
（２人）はぁ！　はい！
Yes, ma'am!
ありました！
I found some!
こっちも　ありました！
Me too!
ここに　パスタ！
Here's some pasta!
ここに　調味料一式と…。
And here's the spices.
おはよう。
どうしたの？
Morning!
What's up?
軸川先輩　副会長　裏の倉庫に
ジャガイモがあるんですけど→
Jikugawa, Vice Prez,
there should be some potatoes in the rear storage,
could you bring them here?
持ってきてもらえますか。
えっ！？　ああ　はいはい。
Huh? Oh, right away.
エレナさん　一緒に手伝って！
はぁ！？　「ちゃん」で　いいわよ。
Elena, could you please help us?
You don't need to ask twice.
カイト。
Kaito!
カイト～！
（いびき）
Kaito!
さっさと起きろ！
ギブ　ギブ　ギブ！
Wake up already!
Uncle! Uncle!
Gammon, you wake up too!
ギャモン君も　さっさと起きる！
あ～！
ほら！　早く着替えて！
はい。
Get dressed up already!
Yes'm...
やめてよ　ノノハ！
今　研究の　いいところなんだよ！
Leave me alone, Nonoha!
I'm at a good point in my research!
アナも
ピンと来たところなんだな～。
And I'm feeling inspired!
いいから　みんなで
ごはん食べる！
Shut up, we're all eating together!
（ギャモン）こいつで　どうだ！
なんの！
How about this?
Oh?
カイト！　ギャモン君！
食事中は　パズルしない！
Kaito! Gammon! No puzzles during meals!
キューちゃんも！　アナも！　没収！
You too, Cubie!
And you, Ana!
Confiscated!
（４人）え～っ！？
ノノハの鬼！　悪魔！
Nonoha, you monster! Demon!
鬼～！　悪魔～！
Monster! Demon!
いいから　さっさと食べる！
Shut the hell up and eat!
副会長…。
Vice President...
Hmm, it seems they're back to their usual selves.
ええ…　いつもの大門君たちに
戻ってる。
会長　これって　一体？
ホント　何でだろうね。
President, what's going on?
I wonder.
（ジュースを飲む音）
うふっ。
Banned During Meals
And Gammon kept on...
それで　いつも　お兄ちゃんが…。
ノノハさん。
ん！？
例のパズルは　解けたの？
Nonoha!
Did you solve that puzzle?
そ　それは…。
Well...
解けなかったら　一緒に居られない
んじゃ　なかったかしら？
I thought you couldn't stay with us any longer then.
パズルは　できないけど　私は　私の
できることをやっていこうって。
I may not be able to solve puzzles, but I'll do what I can...
自分の居場所は自分で作ろうって。
そう決めたんだ。
I'll create my own place.
That's what I thought.
やっぱり分かってない。
えっ！？　何が？
You really don't get it, do you?
Huh? What?
言わないし　教えない。
ん？
Not telling. My lips are sealed.
（ギャモン）どぉ～！
やりやがったなぁ！
You did it now!
What's wrong, Gammon? It's your turn.
どうした？　ギャモン。
お前の番だぜ。
おおっ　俺の番。
あっ　あっ　あっ　あ～！
My turn...
eiyuu kidori itsu datte shinjita muteki no kankaku
I think I'm a hero and believe that I'm invincible.
tatakatte iru no wa chikyuu no tame nanka janai
I'm not fighting for the world.
motto mai peesu de
It's for a more personal,
sou motto shoujikina negai no tame
a more honest wish.
nando to naku kizutsuite mo
No matter how many times I'm hurt